# Pixel-Perfect | Tailwind CSS, SASS

# **Summary**

I've been working as a Front-End Web Developer at TypoTech for 7 years, and now seek a new challenge. I think my experience and skills in JavaScript, HTML, and CSS make me perfect for this role. I've worked in large development teams that have sharpened my technical skills, improved my communication, and made me understand what it takes to meet tight deadlines.

I've recently developed web-based applications for a project management client. My involvement as a designer and a front-end developer has given me the opportunity to manage a diverse range of client requests. I have also proven myself as a team player, which is another crucial requirement for this role.

My keen interest in programming and design helps me find creative solutions to technical challenges and develop visually appealing websites. My extensive knowledge of technical standards helps me manage projects efficiently.

Thank you for your time and consideration. I look forward to meeting you soon and I'm happy to answer any questions you have.

Best & Regards

## **Education**

Newman Theological College Bachelor of Computer Science (BCompSc), Computer science 2012-2015

## **Skills**

- Amazon Web Services
- Front-End Development
- Javascript
- Typescript
- CSS
- Sass
- Tailwind CSS
- HTML
- React
- Vue.js
- Next.js
- Git
- Github
- CI/CD

# **Employment history**

## • Senior Front End Software Engineer | MentorMate

November 2020 - September 2022

NWEA/Questar (Frontend):

- \* Improved graphing module by refactoring and reducing legacy code by 70%.
- \* Added 2 line graph features which increased 40% flexibility when setting up the grid, for instance, how many grid lines per tick step.
- \* Implemented bar graph interaction which is being used in 3 states in the US as part of the exams for more than 10,000 students.
- \* Collaborated with a team of 5 engineers to fix production bugs by 95% per sprint.

#### Lykas (Frontend):

- \* Implemented 15 financial calculators, with a team of 4 engineers to be used by more than 50,000 users across the US to manage personal finances.
- \* Improved website responsiveness by 80% by rewriting legacy react styled-components.

### Senior Front End Developer | Griffin Insurance

September 2019 - February 2020

- \* Made the payment process seamless by redesigning the payment service.
- \* Improved and maintained more than 4 microservices wired with Apache Kafka.
- \* Using React and Vue js, I improved the Underwriter and Customer dashboards.

Technologies Used: Vue Js, React Js, Typescript, Node Js, PostGraphile. Postgresql, Apache Kafka

### • Front End Software Developer | Andela

June 2018 - August 2021

Through Andela, I work for various clients, including: Safaricom PLC, Nairobi (Frontend):

- \* Developed and launched 3 mini apps being used by more than 300,000 use per day.
- \* Developed a full redesign of the Merchant portal with Next js (React), reducing the loading time, user accessibility, and user experience, which saw an increase in user interaction by 60%. Lola, New York (Frontend):
- \* Integrated heap analytics and privy to help in tracking conversation and retention rate which boosted customer retention by 15%.
- \* Saved the company \$9/month by developing a bundle/sets feature and phasing out third-party applications.
- \* Created a mini CMS widely used by the business to create promotional and other pages, reducing creation time by 50%.

\* Onboarded 5 new engineers to the team, product and code base which brought down the onboarding process by a week.

### • Junior Front End (React) Web Developer | Swahilibox

May 2016 - May 2018

Front End Web Developer.

- \* Develop and direct software system testing and validation procedures, programming, and documentation.
- \* Modify existing software to correct errors, to improve its performance.
- \* Analyze user needs and software requirements to determine the feasibility of design within time and cost constraints.
- \* Consult with customers about software system design and maintenance. Technologies Used: Vue Js, Node Js, Laravel, Postgresql, MongoDB

### • HTML Web Developer | BikeNav

Mar 2016 - Apr 2016